[theme music playing]
[tense music playing]
[screaming]
[shattering sound]
[Cora] Their worst act of corruption
was when Mrs. Emilia founded
the Women's Union.
[Camia] We promise to protect you
if you testify against the Ardientes.
[Cora] Testify? You didn't say
anything about that.
-Wait, where are you taking me?
-The mayor is dangerous.
That is why we moved him
to the psychiatric ward.
I think I will have to take
my grandson out of this place.
Arnaldo, you'll get better. But not here.
You will spend time in our rest house.
[Arnaldo] I want Ivy to come with me.
Where do these hallucinations come from?
[Dr. Go] Sometimes, there are truths
buried in our subconscious.
[Ivy] I'm leaving this place.
Arnaldo tried to kill me last night.
Someone tried to choke me,
and I know that it was Arnaldo.
Ivy, just tell me if you need me
and I'll be there.
[Ivy] No, Diego. I have to know
what's happening to Arnaldo.
I have to know why he's acting strange.
[inner voice] There's only one way
to end your suffering.
Kill Ivy Aguas!
No. Stop! No! No!
[foreboding music playing]
[doctor] Julio, I'm sorry.
But your cancer is back.
Bone cancer is very dangerous.
Are you saying my days are numbered?
Julio, we have to conduct more tests.
[foreboding music playing]
[Julio] My time is ending,
and yours is just about to start.
You've grown up to be a fine gentleman,
and I'm so blessed
to have a grandson like you
because of your respect for me.
-[gunshots]
-[screams]
[Raul] Son! Help! Help!
[Julio] You are the son that I never had.
I'm so proud of you.
[dark music playing]
Emilia, Claire…
Pack your things.
We're leaving this house.
-What?
-Huh?!
Yes. I don't want
Arnaldo to come home here.
This house holds too many bad memories.
Mostly, from you.
So, it's better for Arnaldo
not to stay here,
so he can recover faster.
But, Papa, we can't just
pack up and leave!
I've never known you as someone
who makes a decision on a whim, Julio.
And you never will!
Because, unlike you women,
I only make right decisions.
-Oh.
-Papa, what is this about?
This has always been our home.
Please, there's no sense
in being sentimental right now.
You know how I hate repeating myself,
so, please, don't make me.
But, why are we moving?
Where will we move, Papa?
This house is our seat of power.
And that is why I will never
leave my legacy to you.
Because you do not have the brains
nor the gumption of a true Ardiente!
You know what? This house is just that…
another house.
A roof over our heads.
No more, no less!
Okay. No more, no less, Papa. Fine.
[Julio] The true power of the Ardientes
isn't where this mansion is.
Wherever we breathe, lead,
and are held in high regard,
is where the Ardientes' power really is.
All of us Ardientes…
I, and eventually Arnaldo,
will make this family a powerful one.
I have to make sure
that Arnaldo will fulfill
his role as my living legacy.
[tense music playing]
[tense music continues playing]
Emilia, Claire, this will be
our new home sweet home.
I'll be at my office.
Bring all my personal belongings there.
I didn't know about this place.
Well, Auntie, I may have a lot of secrets,
but Papa definitely
has more secrets than I do.
This is one of his properties
that I didn't know about.
I'm sure there's more.
So… does Raul know this place?
Well, Auntie, I don't care.
Papa may have succeeded
in bringing us here…
but I'll still push through with my plans.
Anyway, I have to go.
I'm going to visit Arnaldo.
Bye, Auntie.
Arnaldo is unstable,
and he's been throwing a fit!
I need an ambulance!
No, I can't wait!
I need that ambulance now!
Ivy! Surprise!
Emilia!
How are you?
Oh, Arnaldo!
Hon, surprise! Your mom's here.
How are you? Are you feeling better?
Arnaldo.
I'm… I'm… I'm sorry.
I'm just a little over the edge.
I know, you've been like this
since last night.
Yeah, maybe because of the medicine.
It's giving me mood swings.
Seriously?! I'm just here
to check on you and Ivy!
Oh.
Is the mansion
becoming too boring for you?
Is that why you're bothering us?
-Arnaldo…
-Ivy and I are fine.
That's all you have to know.
Now, please leave.
I'll be right there, hon.
[dark music playing]
[mouthing words]
[phone rings]
-Grandpa?
-Hello, Arnaldo.
How are you? Better? Are you okay?
Well…
Has your mom been there yet?
Well, I was just…
…reading the papers,
and it says here that…
everybody's waiting for you to get well.
So, get well soon.
Get well because we still have
a full campaign ahead of us.
[groans]
[dark music playing]
I'm… I'm far from okay,
Grandpa.
I'm far from okay.
[dark music continues playing]
[line rings]
Hello, Emilia, I have a--
[phone beeps]
DIEGO TORILLO FILES CASE ANEW VERSUS
BROTHER, MAYOR ARNALDO TORILLO
[scoffs]
He's really getting on my nerves.
[line rings]
Colonel Sanggano…
Teach that bastard, Diego, a lesson.
[tense music playing]
[inner voice] You really are nuts!
She doesn't love you!
She's just using you!
No… Stop it! No.
[groaning]
[groans] I don't believe you.
No. I'm gonna get better.
I'll get better! I'll get better!
[grunting and screaming]
[grunts]
[inner voice] You see?
That's what you're good at… playing dumb!
Well, since you can't kill Ivy…
why don't you kill yourself instead?
[no audible dialogue]
Get out! You're not here!
Don't listen to him! No!
[Jepoy] Hold on, what is that?
Someone sent it for Mr. Diego.
Diego? I'll give this to him.
-Diego.
-You have a gift, Batch!
Hey, do you know who it's from?
No, someone just handed it to me.
[Anna] Diego, wait…
That came from the Ardientes.
Whatever's in there
is dangerous. Don't open it.
How will we know if we don't open it?
[murmurs]
[Anna] Don't open it, Diego!
You have to be careful!
-Don't worry…
-What's inside?
Diego, what if a bomb's in there?
[suspenseful music playing]
-[snake hisses]
-[screams]
[Anna] Jepoy! Jepoy! Jepoy!
[snake hisses]
[Fernan] Be careful, Diego.
-Don't! Jepoy, wait.
-Stand back… Be careful!
-Diego, be careful!
-Be careful, Batch.
[suspenseful music playing]
[screams]
[Pandoy] Diego! Easy.
[Fernan] Get the box! Get the box!
-Look at it!
-What?!
-Jepoy, put it back.
-Slowly.
-[Anna] Be careful!
-Put it there, Jepoy.
[Anna] Please be careful.
Be careful.
-Easy.
-Be careful.
-Hold it there.
-Got it?
Get that snake a round-trip ticket
so we can send it back to Julio Ardiente!
-See if he likes it!
-That's right.
Next time, don't just receive packages
unless they're from
the members of this party.
Do you understand?
-Yes, ma'am.
-Yes, ma'am. Yes, ma'am.
[Julio] This is a cobra,
one of the most poisonous
snakes in the world.
If you're reading this,
it means you got lucky.
But I'll make sure you won't
be as lucky next time.
Just wait for me out here.
Miss, is this the end of the queue?
-Yes it is, ma'am.
-Thank you.
[woman] Next, please.
[phone rings]
-Hello, Diego?
-Hello, Auntie?
Be careful over there.
Julio Ardiente sent a snake here.
So the Ardientes are trying
to scare us again?
Do they really think
their antics will frighten us?
They're just fueling our courage.
Just be careful, Auntie.
I will, Diego.
Next, please.
-Good morning.
I'd just like to ask for
records of the Women's Union.
The group has long been abolished, ma'am.
It's for research purposes.
I'll use it as a prototype
for further studies.
I plan to pursue a master's degree.
-Mm. Just a minute.
-Thank you.
[woman] Hello, ma'am Eds.
Someone here is asking
about the Women's Union.
Do you know where our files are?
Uh… Okay, ma'am. Thank you.
Ma'am, I'm sorry but we have no records.
None? No records? What do you mean?
I'm asking for public documents.
We have none.
Just come back when my boss is available.
She's on leave.
[woman] Next, please.
Here. Keep the change, man.
Because when I exit that door,
I'd be luckier than a lottery winner.
Thank you.
[unsettling music playing]
[inner voice] What are
you waiting for? Fire it.
Come on. Fire it.
Fire it. You're useless, Arnaldo.
Besides, you're a murderer.
You killed Carlotta, Nimfa,
and other innocent people.
All for the love of a woman
you will never have
because she's lying to you.
You're an idiot, Arnaldo. You're stupid.
A moron! Kill yourself! Do it!
-Ah…
-Who are you?
Good afternoon. I'm Jerry Dimalanta.
Can I talk to the mayor?
You again? Ivy, this man…
Why are you following me?
Don't you dare touch me again!
How did you find me here?
I have many bodyguards.
Emilia, relax. How can I help you?
I just want to talk to the mayor.
He needs to know what I know.
You have to trust me.
If you let me talk to him,
I'm sure you won't regret it.
Especially not the mayor.
[tense music playing]
No! No!
[groans]
[knocks on door]
Arnaldo.
Hey, open the door.
[knocking continues]
-This isn't over.
-Son, somebody wants to see you.
This isn't over.
Emilia, where did you meet Mr. Jerry?
He might be a spy for Diego.
Oh, Ivy, just don't mind him.
He must be a fanatic.
Anyway, how are you and Arnaldo?
Well, please tell the congressman
that he's getting worse.
We need to re-admit him to the psych ward.
I know you came here
to keep an eye on things
and report to the congressman.
So, tell him that.
Or, I have a better idea.
What if you stay here so we can
both take care of Arnaldo?
-What do you think?
-Oh.
Ivy, can we skip
the depressing topics for later?
You know, I came here
not just for Arnaldo.
I came here to talk to you
regarding my candidacy
because you still haven't
given me any straight answer.
So, will you support me or not?
Doesn't this annoy you?
You always want to talk
about your political career
whenever you visit me.
[sighs] You're lucky I'm a patient woman.
Fine. Let's talk about it,
but before that…
I need to know everything, Emilia.
All the good and not-so-good
things you did before.
I want to know all your secrets.
Because from there,
I'll know how to stand for you,
how to support you,
and how to protect you.
Do you remember
what you told me at the bar?
About billions. Remember?
I--I said that?
-Really? I did?
-Yes.
[chuckles]
Me and my big mouth, honestly.
When I drink, that's my problem.
That's always been my problem, Ivy.
-So, is it true?
-I spill too much…
-when I'm drunk.
-Is it true, Emilia?
[sighs] Okay, okay.
I must admit…
yeah, that was during my time as mayor.
Um, I'd get commissions.
But that was before.
-Before.
-[phone rings]
Wait, I just have an important call.
Hello?
[Emilia] Yes?
[phone rings]
Mom?
I didn't get any information here…
at the city hall.
But I'm sure of one thing.
The Ardientes are hiding something
in the group Emilia established.
Mom, Emilia just told me
something that matches up…
with the information you're getting.
She's possibly getting her stolen funds…
through that commission.
Don't worry.
I won't stop investigating this.
I'll find out what they're hiding.
Okay, Mom.
[tense music playing]
[Jerry] Oh, Mayor.
Hurry up, I don't have time.
I'm sure you won't regret this, Mayor.
You're wasting my time.
Relax, Mayor!
I don't need anything from you.
Truth is, you're the one who needs me.
And I'm sure you'll give me a lot of money
for what I'm going to give you.
[unsettling music playing]
A broken cell phone?
What am I supposed to do with this thing?
Smash it on your head?
Mayor. Mayor.
First, ask what exactly
is in that cellphone.
This contains the dark truth
about your beloved Ivy.
[upbeat music playing]
[Nimfa] I'm sure about this, ma'am Emilia.
I'll find out just who she is.
[Emilia] Take a video, and
send it to me immediately.
Pick up, Emilia.
Ma'am Emilia… I know the truth!
-Ivy Aguas and Lily--
-No!
Mayor Arnaldo! Mayor…
-You need to know that Ivy is---
-That's not true!
[Fernan] Nimfa!
-Mister Fernan!
-Nimfa!
This is Nimfa's cellphone.
You'll find Nimfa and Emilia's
text message exchanges there.
[tense music playing]
[breathing deeply]
Mayor Ardiente needs to see this.
Mayor, just watch the video.
To see is to believe!
[tense music continues playing]
[Emilia] Ivy!
Ivy, I hate to say this, but I have to go.
I have an emergency.
Emergency? What happened? Are you okay?
Well, let's just say a little bird told me
that somebody is snooping
in my old playground.
Well, at least, you know it isn't me.
I'll tell you more about it tomorrow.
Tell Arnaldo I left already. Bye-bye.
-Take care.
-Thank you.
-Mom.
-Lily, dear.
[Ivy] I'm sorry that I had
to point a gun at you earlier.
[Camia] It's all right, Lily.
I understand why.
Ivy is Lily?
Ivy and Lily are one?
They're the same person?
[Ivy] Mr. Mayor? My name is Ivy.
Ivy Aguas.
[Arnaldo sighs] You really are
something else, Miss Aguas.
Thank you for investing
in our project, by the way.
I invested a lot, Mr. Mayor.
I'll expect a lot in return.
[Arnaldo] I want to be a senator.
I need your help.
[Ivy] The farmer's lands. Give it to me.
[Arnaldo] Are you doing this
for the farmers or for Diego?
Well, Mr. Mayor, it's not my fault
your brother moves faster… than you do.
All this time?
[Ivy] Diego and I still see each other.
But I told him to stay away.
Because I know I'm sure
of my feelings for you.
Arnaldo, I'm not playing you. I love you.
I love you, Arnaldo.
[Julio] I couldn't help but notice…
you and Miss Aguas are growing closer.
It seems like you're drunk
on love, or should I say lust?
Don't be stupid.
Because of your actions, you're
starting to look like a fool.
[Arnaldo] A lifetime of love
and happiness… with me.
Ivy Aguas, I love you. Will you marry me?
Yes, Arnaldo!
All this time, she's been lying to me?
[Arnaldo] You know, sometimes I
think you're just leading me on.
One minute, you're hot,
the next thing, you're cold.
What do you really want?
[Julio] Arnaldo, I have a suspicion
that Miss Aguas is hiding something.
Damn it, Madrigal!
I told you not to lose her.
Mayor, I'm sorry. It was my mistake.
Did you do it intentionally?
What are you doing here, Madrigal?
I called your number one man over
to ask what kind of gift you might like
because your birthday's coming up soon.
Grandpa, Mom, you have to see this.
Madrigal?
[Julio] We finally caught the rat.
Kill Madrigal in front of us
to prove that we're no different.
[groans]
[Ivy] I won't taint my hands
just to prove my loyalty!
Everything I did for her.
All this time, she's using me?
She's using me?!
She's using me.
Lily Cruz is alive, Aunt Claire.
She's Camia's backer. She's alive.
[Claire] Lily Cruz? Camia's daughter?
[Arnaldo] You know what's funny?
Mama mentioned that…
because you didn't tell us
you were adopted,
there's a possibility that
you could be Lily Cruz.
This Lily Cruz is the one backing up…
-Camia and Diego.
-Arnaldo!
[Ivy] What you saw was the
only thing we were doing.
[Arnaldo] What were you talking about?
How the two of you
will stab me behind my back?
[Ivy] If you don't believe me,
if you think I'm betraying you,
let's just stop this.
We should call off our wedding.
[Nimfa] She's the one feeding
information to Diego's camp.
-That's not true!
-She's Diego's spy…
-…within the Ardiente family!
She's just using you.
-That's not true!
-Mayor, you need to know…
-that Ivy is--
-That's not true!
You need to believe me,
Arnaldo, not that farmhand.
If you believe me, we'll get married.
I believe you. I believe
everything that you say!
[Ivy] That's all I need.
We'll push through with the wedding.
-I've got Ivy Aguas.
-Well, I have you now!
I can easily kill you
and make it look
like you committed suicide,
just like what I did to Carlotta.
Monster!
-I didn't mean to!
-You monster! I don't love you!
I'll never love a demon like you!
You're a demon!
-You love me.
-I don't love you!
You love me.
Arrest this man! Take him to prison!
Arrest Arnaldo!
[Julio] Stop them! I said, stop them!
[tense music intensifies]
She used me. She used me…
Damn. That bitch.
That bitch. That bitch.
That bitch. She used me.
Mayor, you look like
you're about to kill someone.
Mayor!
[grunts]
[dark music playing]
We've succeeded in refiling
the case in the new RTC branch
here in Ardiente.
Contrary to popular belief,
not all RTC branches
are controlled by the Ardientes.
This one particular judge
is connected to the Court of Appeals
and is a well-known
critic of the Ardientes.
I'll just update you about the case.
Listen, everyone.
Our fight continues.
We shouldn't be afraid of the Ardientes,
and no one will back out of the campaign.
-[all] That's right!
-For a new Ardiente!
[all] For a new Ardiente!
[clapping]
[Julio] Sanggano.
What was Diego Torillo's
reaction to the gift I sent him?
He was frightened, Congressman.
[laughs]
Their uninvited guest caused a
commotion at their headquarters.
-Sir!
-Where's Emilia?
-Ma'am Emilia told us not to let you in.
-I need to talk to her.
Let me in! Let me in.
-Sir, she's not here.
-I said let me in!
-I told you, she's not here!
-What did you say?
-She's not here.
-Let me go.
-Sir, please.
-Step aside!
Diego Torillo's group
is campaigning today, right?
You know, I have been very,
very patient with them,
which is actually a very rare thing.
I could've just stomped on him
and crushed him…
like dust.
I think you're getting soft, Congressman.
Maybe you can say that.
Perhaps…
I think I was really affected
by what happened to Arnaldo.
But I am done trying to be good and decent
about this whole fiasco.
I want you to bring me Diego Torillo.
Any which way.
Dead or alive, it doesn't matter.
Yes, sir.
Good morning.
What's our schedule for today?
Well, Dr. Go is coming today
for your checkup.
Cancel that.
There's no need for one.
For some reason, I feel good.
No, actually, I feel really good.
I don't know why.
I haven't felt this good in months.
Good. I'll call your mom
to tell her we're going home.
No, no, no, no. Not so fast.
Why don't we stay here first
and enjoy the rest house?
You know, make the most of our lives
before returning to Poblacion Ardiente.
Let's go home tomorrow.
Give me this one more day
with you, and I promise…
we'll have so much fun.
How does that sound?
Great! Let's eat.
Are you acting like this
because you're sick
or because you're playing tricks on me?
I'll find out what's going on
in your mind, Arnaldo.
[Diego] Get this printed as well.
[man] Here are the remaining posters.
[Diego] Okay, put it over there.
[indistinct chatter]
Excuse me.
Son.
Dad.
How are you?
I'm okay, Dad. How are you?
Well… I have something
important I want to tell you.
It's about your campaign for later.
I don't think you should go.
Julio's planning something
against you, and it's not good.
He's going to kidnap you
and kill you, son.
Julio's already attempted
to kill me several times.
I can take care of myself, Dad.
I know you can, son.
But what about your supporters?
Can you stand to see them getting hurt?
And getting hurt is just one
thing, what if they get killed?
You won't always be able
to protect yourself.
You need allies, someone on your side.
You need the protection
of strong people, like Jaguar.
But, Dad, that man is a criminal.
[scoffs]
Well, whatever he is,
what's important is you're
fighting for the same things.
He wants to bring down the Ardientes too.
If that happens, if he protects you,
you'll be ruling over Ardiente--
Hang on, Dad…
Do you know Jaguar?
Why do you want me to side with him?
Are you working together?
Dad, no matter what happens,
I won't align myself with Jaguar.
I'll protect my supporters
without gripping the edge of a knife.
[tense music playing]
Hon.
Come on. Swim.
[tense music playing]
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Can I ask you something?
Why do you love me?
I can't answer that.
As other people have put it,
there's no right or wrong reason
why you love somebody.
It's my turn to ask you something.
Sure.
How was your talk with Mister Jerry?
-Mr. Jerry?
-What did you talk about?
Well, we had an interesting
conversation, and then he left.
I didn't see him leave, Arnaldo.
Well, that is because you were with Mom.
You know what, Ivy?
Let's not talk about it.
Sit down.
Let's focus on the now.
Here, with me.
The present is so delicate
that we don't know
what tomorrow will bring.
But you know, I've been thinking…
if I die today…
I'll have it.
I'd rather die with you.
And I'll be fine with it.
I love you.
I really, really love you.
[tense music playing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[suspenseful music continues]
-What are you doing here?
-Arnaldo.
Well…
[Ivy scoffs]
I was waiting for you.
Ivy. Let's go.
-What?
-Let's go.
Don't you want to?
I'd love to, but we have
to do something first.
Get dressed.
Okay? Go.
-Okay.
-Get dressed.
-Ouch!
-We'll go somewhere.
I'll discover what you're hiding.
And once I do, I'll finish you off myself.
[indistinct chatter]
[woman] My goodness! It stinks!
I'll call the authorities!
-What's happening?
-There's a dead body.
[eerie music]
[unsettling music playing]
[Arnaldo] What are you
talking about? Revenge?
You don't know a thing! You don't!
You have no proof.
Unless you can prove everything
you're accusing Ivy of,
I won't believe you.
How was your talk with Mister Jerry?
Well, we had an interesting
conversation, and then he left.
[unsettling music playing]
[tense music playing]
[tense music continues playing]
[tense music intensifies]
Mom.
Lily, dear.
[ominous music playing]
[line rings]
It is an honor for me and
for my colleagues to serve you.
Our aim is to give happiness
and hope to our constituents
here in this home for the aged.
I highly respect you,
grandfathers and grandmothers.
Diego, pick up.
We have a few things to give you.
And we hope you like them.
[applause]
Why did you throw it there?
Did I tell you to throw it there?
Get that body, clean it,
and take it somewhere else. Okay?
Because if you don't,
your body will lie in its place.
-Do you understand?
-Yes, Mayor.
-Go. Go! Now!
-Yes.
[line ringing]
Arnaldo.
Where've you been?
I've been looking for you.
I just asked the bodyguards
to check the car.
Okay.
You know what? Um… I was thinking.
What if… we go to the place
we're supposed to go to alone?
No bodyguards. What do you think?
I like it. Good idea.
So, where are you taking me?
I can't tell you.
It's a surprise.
But, I promise you, you'll have fun.
Exciting. Okay. You go ahead.
I'll just get my things.
Okay. I'll meet you outside.
I'll go get something too.
[tense music playing]
Damn you, Arnaldo.
I'll kill you before
you find out who I really am.
[tense music playing]
I'll make you pay for lying to me,
Ivy Aguas.
But, before that…
you'll make me happy.
I'm jealous of your
close friendship with this…
Lily Cruz.
I'm not talking about
the Lily Cruz that you're with.
She's an impostor. That's right.
I'm going to make her regret
all the things that she did to me,
and then, I'll kill her.
There's a bomb, everyone! There's a bomb!
[laughs]
We're the only ones here,
so you can do whatever you want.
I can do whatever I want.
I want to hear it straight
from your mouth.
You're Lily Cruz, right?
Yes, I'm Lily Cruz!
[theme music playing]